In this clip, we're going to talk about penalty kicks.
In indoor soccer, there are two types of penalty kicks.
What I'm going to tell you about is the run up pad.
Now basically this is very different than the outdoor version of a PK.
This is when a flagrant foul, usually a blue card style foul, is committed, and there was possibly an offensive chance for a goal.
So the referee will pull all the players back behind the red line, and the person who gets awarded the kick, gets the ball started at the red line, and the goal keeper has to start with his heels on the goal line, and once the referee blows his whistle, those two can come out, and then it's basically one V one.
When the shot is taken, if it's missed the play is dead, and I believe the team that was awarded the kick automatically gets a free kick after the PK.
The other PK is just one of your standard penalty kicks where everybody is placed outside the red line.
You get one of these kicks when a penalty or a foul occurs inside the goalie box.
Again it's a smaller goalie box, so these are a little bit rarer than the one V one penalty kicks.
The ball is placed at the penalty kick dot that is on the field, a little bit in front of the penalty box.
At that point, the keeper must stay on the goal line, the official will blow his whistle, and once the ball is touched, the keeper is allowed to move from the line, to save the ball.
It's a very short shot, so usually it's taken with some sort of accuracy or power.
Once the ball is kicked, if the ball hits the wall, but does not touch another person, then the person kicking the penalty kick is not allowed to touch the ball, it must touch someone else before hand.
If it does go off the keeper, then the player is allowed to then try to get the rebound into the goal.
But once it's touched, or once the ball is kicked towards the goal, everybody else is allowed to enter the play of field.